export const FINANCIALACCOUNTINGA2017 = [

{
id: "question1",
question:  "1. Customers use the financial statement of a company to?",
A: "Assess the financial position of the business",
B: "Regulate their activities",
C: "Ascertain the taxable profit of the business",
D: "Be sure of the extent of job security",
answer: "A. Assess the financial position of the business",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question2",
question:  "2. The claim on the assets of a business by outsiders is?",
A: "Capital",
B: "Liabilities",
C: "Reserves",
D: "Provisions",
answer: "B. Liabilities",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question3",
question:  "3. A document sent by a bank to its current account customers detailing their transactions over a given period is?",
A: "Bank reconciliation statement",
B: "Bank statement",
C: "Credit transfer",
D: "Banker’s advice",
answer: "B. Bank statement",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question4",
question:  "4. Which of the following items will not be entered in the adjusted cash book?",
A: "Dishonoured Cheques",
B: "Direct payments to banks",
C: "Uncredited Cheques",
D: "Standing order payment",
answer: "C. Uncredited Cheques",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question5",
question:  "5. If a petty cashier has a cash float of Le39,000 and Le37,500 is spent, he will be reimbursed with?",
A: "Le40,500",
B: "Le39,000",
C: "Le37,500",
D: "Le1,500",
answer: "C. Le37,500",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question6",
question:  "6. A suspense account is used in the?",
A: "Prevention of errors",
B: "ion of errors",
C: "Detection of errors",
D: "Creation of errors",
answer: "B. Correction of errors",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question7",
question:  "7. A credit purchase of GHc200 from P. osae was posted to the account of P. Osei. This is an error of?",
A: "Principle",
B: "Commission",
C: "Omission",
D: "Original entry",
answer: "B. Commission",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question8",
question:  "8. Discount allowed on goods invoiced at GHc100,000 was calculated at the rate of 20% instead of 10%. the error is corrected by debiting?",
A: "Customer account with GHc20,000; crediting discount allowed with GHc20,000",
B: "Discount allowed with GHc10,000; crediting customer’s account with GHc10,000",
C: "Customers account’s account with GHc10,000; crediting discount allowed with GHc10,000",
D: "Discount allowed with GHc20,000; crediting cash with GHc10,000",
answer: "C. Customers account’s account with GHc10,000; crediting discount allowed with GHc10,000",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question9",
question:  "9. The balance sheet equation shows?",
A: "Current assets minus current liabilities",
B: "The differences between fixed assets ad current liabilities",
C: "Assets ad sources of financing them",
D: "Sources of funding owner’s equity",
answer: "A. Current assets minus current liabilities",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question10",
question:  "10. The effect of profit when the closing stock is understated is?",
A: "Increase in profit",
B: "Decrease in profit",
C: "No change in profit",
D: "Appropriation of profit",
answer: "A. Increase in profit",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question11",
question:  "11. Which of the following describes a trial balance?",
A: "It shows all the entries in the books",
B: "It reveals the financial position of a business",
C: "It is a list of accounting balances on the book",
D: "It is a list of special accounting balances on the book",
answer: "C. It is a list of accounting balances on the book",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question12",
question:  "12. The accounts of Jute enterprise in the books of a supplier will be a?",
A: "Nominal account in the general ledger",
B: "Personal account in the sales ledger",
C: "Personal account in the purchases ledger",
D: "Real account in the general ledger",
answer: "C. Personal account in the purchases ledger",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question13",
question:  "13. Which of the following accounts are found in the nominal ledger? \nI. Advertising \nII. Motor repairs \nIII. Additions to motor vehicle",
A: "I and II only",
B: "I and III only",
C: "II and III only",
D: "I, II and III",
answer: "B. I and III only",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question14",
question:  "14. Accounts payable is classified as a?",
A: "Prepayment",
B: "Provision",
C: "Current liability",
D: "Long term liability",
answer: "C. Current liability",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question15",
question:  "15. The accounting concept that provides that an accounting statement should not be influenced by personal opinion is?",
A: "Materiality",
B: "Periodicity",
C: "Objectivity",
D: "Conservation",
answer: "C. Objectivity",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question16",
question:  "16. The prudence concept demands that?",
A: "Care is exercised in recognition of profit",
B: "Loss should not be anticipated",
C: "Profit should be reported",
D: "Income should be recognized and disclosed",
answer: "D. Income should be recognized and disclosed",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question17",
question:  "17. Carriage outward expenses of a business are treated in the?",
A: "Balance sheet",
B: "Income surplus account",
C: "Profit and loss account",
D: "Trading account",
answer: "C. Profit and loss account",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question18",
question:  "18. The cost of transporting purchased goods to the warehouse is charged to the?",
A: "Profit and loss account",
B: "Appropriation account",
C: "Trading account",
D: "Income surplus account",
answer: "C. Trading account",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question19",
question:  "19. An organization purchased an equipment for GHc112,000. it is expected to be used for 6years then sold for GHc16,000. what is the annual amount of depreciation if the straight-line method is used?",
A: "GHc16,000",
B: "GHc15,000",
C: "GHc12,800",
D: "GHc12,000",
answer: "A. GHc16,000",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question20",
question:  "20. The credit sale for the month is?",
A: "D36,000",
B: "D31,000",
C: "D20,000",
D: "D10,000",
answer: "A. D36,000",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question21",
question:  "21. The total sale for the month is?",
A: "D36,000",
B: "D31,000",
C: "D30,000",
D: "D20,000",
answer: "C. D30,000",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question22",
question:  "22. The excess of the market value of goods produced over the cost of production is?",
A: "Profit on manufacturing",
B: "Net profit",
C: "Goodwill",
D: "Gross profit",
answer: "A. Profit on manufacturing",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question23",
question:  "23. Factory wages form part of?",
A: "Administration cost",
B: "Selling and distribution cost",
C: "Overhead cost",
D: "Prime cost",
answer: "C. Overhead cost",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question24",
question:  "24. Production cost of a manufacturing firm is made up of?",
A: "Indirect materials and prime cost",
B: "Factory overheads and prime cost",
C: "Direct materials and wages",
D: "Factory overheads and direct materials",
answer: "B. Factory overheads and prime cost",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question25",
question:  "25. In a manufacturing enterprise depreciation of plant is treated in the?",
A: "Trading account",
B: "Profit and loss account",
C: "Manufacturing account",
D: "Appropriation account",
answer: "C. Manufacturing account",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question26",
question:  "26. The purpose of keeping sales and purchases ledger control account is to?",
A: "Match credit sales and credit purchases",
B: "Equate debtors balance to creditors balance",
C: "Verify total debtors and total creditors balances",
D: "Determine cash sales and cash purchases",
answer: "C. Verify total debtors and total creditors balances",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question27",
question:  "27. Which of the following items will appear in the total creditors’ account?",
A: "Discount allowed",
B: "Credit sales",
C: "Discount received",
D: "Cash purchases",
answer: "C. Discount received",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question28",
question:  "28. A disadvantage of the single entry system of bookkeeping is that?",
A: "The profit for the period is reduced",
B: "It is difficult to determine profit for the period",
C: "Total sales for the period is reduced",
D: "The owner of the firm withdraws money from the enterprise",
answer: "B. It is difficult to determine profit for the period",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question29",
question:  "29. Which of the following accounts or statements is used to determine credit purchases figure in an incomplete record",
A: "Bank account",
B: "Control account",
C: "Profit and loss account",
D: "Statement of affairs",
answer: "B. Control account",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question30",
question:  "30. A trader sells goods at an average margin of 2%. His cost of sales for the month amounted to N720,000. What is his profit figure?",
A: "N90,000",
B: "N864,000",
C: "N840,000",
D: "N180,000",
answer: "D. N180,000",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question31",
question:  "31. Donation to a club is?",
A: "Credited to the income and expenditure account",
B: "Credited to the receipts and payment account",
C: "Debited to the income and expenditure account",
D: "Debited to donations account",
answer: "A. Credited to the income and expenditure account",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question32",
question:  "32. A statement of affairs shows?",
A: "Receipts and payments",
B: "Revenue and expenditure",
C: "Financial position",
D: "Profit or loss",
answer: "C. Financial position",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question33",
question:  "33. In a not for profit-making organization, the receipts and payments account is the equivalent of?",
A: "Profit and loss account",
B: "Income and expenditure account",
C: "Cash book",
D: "Balance sheet",
answer: "C. Cash book",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question34",
question:  "34. Where there is no agreement between the partners, the partnership act states that?",
A: "5% interest is to be paid on capital",
B: "Profit and losses are t be shared in proportion to their capital",
C: "50% interest is to be charged on drawings",
D: "No salary is to be paid to partner",
answer: "D. No salary is to be paid to partners",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question35",
question:  "35. Interest on drawings are debited in the?",
A: "Partners current account and credited to the appropriation account",
B: "Drawings account and credited to the profit and loss account",
C: "Profit and loss account and credited to the partners current account",
D: "Profit and loss account and credited to the partners drawing account",
answer: "A. Partners current account and credited to the appropriation account",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question36",
question:  "36. Goodwill may be brought into the books when?",
A: "No partner retires",
B: "Assets are more than liabilities",
C: "Profit of the period is high",
D: "A new partner is admitted",
answer: "D. A new partner is admitted",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question37",
question:  "37. Working capital is the excess of?",
A: "Current assets over fixed assets",
B: "Current liabilities over current assets",
C: "Fixed assets over current liabilities",
D: "Current assets over current liabilities",
answer: "D. Current assets over current liabilities",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question38",
question:  "38. Share premium is classified in the balance as?",
A: "Fixed capital",
B: "Capital reserve",
C: "Revenue reserve",
D: "Short term capital",
answer: "B. Capital reserve",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question39",
question:  "39. The percentage of gross profit to sales is?",
A: "61.82%",
B: "38.17%",
C: "28.49%",
D: "14.25%",
answer: "B. 38.17%",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question40",
question:  "40. What is the rate of stock turnover?",
A: "7 times",
B: "6 times",
C: "5 times",
D: "4 times",
answer: "D. 4 times",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question41",
question:  "41. When allotment of shares is made applicants for shares of a company become?",
A: "Promoters",
B: "Creditors",
C: "Debtors",
D: "Shareholders",
answer: "D. Shareholders",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question42",
question:  "42. The objective of a departmental account is to ascertain the?",
A: "Number of staff in the department",
B: "Departmental performance",
C: "Stock help by the departments",
D: "Departmental turnover",
answer: "B. Departmental performance",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question43",
question:  "43. In departmental accounting, when goods are sent from one department to another for sales, the transaction is treated as?",
A: "Interdepartmental transfer",
B: "Interdepartmental sales",
C: "Intra-departmental transfer",
D: "Intra-departmental sales",
answer: "A. Interdepartmental transfer",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question44",
question:  "44. A branch that keeps its own records prepares the records of transactions with the head office in the?",
A: "Branch current account",
B: "Branch stock account",
C: "Head office current account",
D: "Profit and loss account",
answer: "A. Branch current account",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question45",
question:  "45. The accounting entries when goods are sold on credit at the branch are debited?",
A: "Branch debtors account; credit sales account",
B: "Branch current account; credit sales account",
C: "Branch debtors account; credit head office current account",
D: "Head office current account; credit sales account",
answer: "A. Branch debtors account; credit sales account",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question46",
question:  "46. Which of the following is not a method of charging goods to the branch by its head office?",
A: "Net realization value",
B: "Cost price",
C: "Cost plus profit",
D: "Selling price",
answer: "A. Net realization value",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question47",
question:  "47. Recurrent expenditure for the year is?",
A: "D112,000",
B: "D84,000",
C: "D77,000",
D: "D49,00",
answer: "B. D84,000",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question48",
question:  "48. Capital expenditure for the local government is?",
A: "D473,000",
B: "D438,000",
C: "D422,000",
D: "D410,000",
answer: "B. D438,000",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question49",
question:  "49. A reserve is an amount?",
A: "Set aside from profit for an unknown liability",
B: "Of loss from trading activities",
C: "Of profit from trading activities",
D: "Set aside not to meet any liability",
answer: "A. Set aside from profit for an unknown liability",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question50",
question:  "50. An amount set aside to meet expenses whose value is not certain is a?",
A: "Reserve",
B: "Liability",
C: "Provision",
D: "Pre",
answer: "C. Provision",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},


]